ANTONI KARASAVOV

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

07741 118 196 <u>karasavov@gmail.com</u> London, UK

Summary

Results focused senior software engineer with over 10 years of experience in building web applications with Ruby on Rails backends and your favourite JavaScript framework on the frontend.

Areas of expertise

Ruby	Rul	by	on Ra	ails	HTML/CSS/JS		
EmberJS V		ueJS	ReactJS		Git	TDD	
PostgreSQL			ElasticSearch		AWS	3	
APIs	APIs Agile		Heroku		UI/UX		

Experience

METROPOLITAN THAMES VALLEY HOUSING ASSOCIATION

Senior Ruby on Rails Consultant, February 2020 — Present, London, UK

Mentoring/Coaching part:

- Lead a team of two junior and a senior Ruby on Rails programmers through transitioning the development for a suit of applications from a third party agency to in-house.
- Help build the in-house team capabilities by mentoring, reviewing code, pairing with juniors and taking
 detours into Rails internals, while providing regular practical learning sessions, based on a chosen
 topic, e.g. REST APIs, HTTP protocol, Network programming, sockets, OSI model and some more
 theoretical topics, such as OOP, Composition, Interfaces, Dependency Injection, etc.
- Participate in transitioning work sprints where we've successfully transferred domain knowledge of the application to the internal team.
- · Lead interviewee worksim sessions for a senior Ruby on Rails role.

Practical/Application coding part:

- Improve the handling of connections for a custom SQL Server library by introducing connection pooling
- Review and provide feedback on code affecting various parts of each application, like integration with third party APIs, payments, handling external service dependencies.
- Enhance test coverage and fix intermittently failing specs, which eliminates bad builds and boosts team confidence in the CI/CD.
- Pay back some tech-debt by modernising outdated libraries and refactoring some of the code used for handling data from their "middleware" and payment gateway applications, while taking the junior team through the process.

CABOODLE STORAGE

Senior Software Engineering Consultant, January 2018 — December 2019, London, UK

- Build, test and deploy a user facing web application in Ruby on Rails and VueJS that enables customers to place online orders, request collections and returns, and manage a catalogue of their belongings.
- Cut payment gateway costs by implementing Stripe for payments processing and recurring billing.
- Integrate with DPD and other courier APIs in order to improve visibility and tracking of customer orders.
- Build a bespoke Ruby On Rails warehouse management system which reduces warehouse management complexity with support for third-party app integration via exposing a fully documented and tested REST API.
- Build a small VueJS based electron print-server app that enables warehouse staff to encode RFID transponders and print labels to any printer in the facility from any one workstation.
- Achieve top loading speeds and a constant above 95% Google PageSpeed by continuously monitoring and optimising the Caboodle front-end.
- Drive customer engagement and increase retention by aiding the marketing team in running various A/B tests, optimising the checkout flow and implementing different measuring tools.

PLANDEK

Senior JavaScript Developer, September 2016 — January 2018, London, UK

- Lead a front-end team in building a business intelligence EmberJS application on top of the company's existing data APIs and infrastructure.
- Increase usability and user engagement by developing a modular charting engine based on EmberJS components, service objects and D3.
- Cut down cycle times and dramatically reduce QA team's efforts by implementing a system that is capable of running different versions of the application by loading code from different Git branches.
- Proactively get involved in maintaining a Rails API-only app in order to aid faster customer onboarding.
- Report directly to product team and CEO, participate in weekly sprint meetings and contribute to overall improvement of the product.

ARTIRIX

Full-stack Web Developer, May 2011 — September 2016, London, UK

- Work with a team of Ruby on Rails and Python developers for the complete re-write of DMGT's holiday sales website - MailTravel, which led to an 80% increase in conversions only a few months after the launch of the project.
- Increase the number of user-bookable holiday packages listed on the website by developing and testing integrations for various holiday provider APIs, including Newmarket Holidays and Riviera Travel.
- Provide ongoing support for a Ruby on Rails/Python/Elasticsearch platform which powers classifieds websites for clients such as Globrix, Estates Gazette, PropertyLink, Dow Jones, Teletext Holidays, Chestertons, KFH.
- Lead the front-end development for a rare disease startup RareMark. Work closely with the product team to improve usability and ease of finding relevant academic articles and papers. Front-end was built with a custom framework, based on BackboneJS.

VERTINITY

Junior Web Developer, June 2009 - April 2011, Plovdiv, BG

- Enable faster idea-to-market delivery for company's clients by introducing and adopting MVC frameworks like CakePHP and OpenCart.
- Work on existing jQuery and framework-less frontends for large e-commerce clients in order to improve customer experience and increase conversions.
- Build and deploy custom PHP websites for various clients.
- Get invaluable mentorship from top engineers in the industry on various software development topics.

Education

KINGSTON UNIVERSITY

MSc Software Engineering, 2012

CITY UNIVERSITY OF SEATTLE

BSc Business Administration, 2010